<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<root>
<name>arrayCopy()</name>

<category>Data</category>

<subcategory>Array Functions</subcategory>

<type></type>

<example>
<image></image>
<code><![CDATA[
String[] north = { "OH", "IN", "MI" };
String[] south = { "GA", "FL", "NC" };
arrayCopy(north, south);
println(south);
// Prints updated array contents to the console:
// [0] "OH"
// [1] "IN"
// [2] "MI"
]]></code>
</example>

<example>
<image></image>
<code><![CDATA[
String[] north = { "OH", "IN", "MI"};
String[] south = { "GA", "FL", "NC"}; 
arrayCopy(north, 1, south, 0, 2);
println(south);
// Prints updated array contents to the console:
// [0] "IN"
// [1] "MI"
// [2] "NC"
]]></code>
</example>

<description><![CDATA[
Copies an array (or part of an array) to another array. The <b>src</b> array is copied to the <b>dst</b> array, beginning at the position specified by <b>srcPosition</b> and into the position specified by <b>dstPosition</b>. The number of elements to copy is determined by <b>length</b>. Note that copying values overwrites existing values in the destination array. To append values instead of overwriting them, use <b>concat()</b>.<br/>
<br/>
The simplified version with only two arguments &mdash; <b>arrayCopy(src, dst)</b> &mdash; copies an entire array to another of the same size. It is equivalent to <b>arrayCopy(src, 0, dst, 0, src.length)</b>.<br/>
<br/>
Using this function is far more efficient for copying array data than iterating through a <b>for()</b> loop and copying each element individually.
<br/>
This function only copies references, which means that for most purposes it only copies one-dimensional arrays (a single set of brackets). If used with a two (or three or more) dimensional array, it will only copy the references at the first level, because a two dimensional array is simply an "array of arrays". This does not produce an error, however, because this is often the desired behavior. 
<br/>
Internally, this function calls Java's <a href="http://docs.oracle.com/javase/7/docs/api/java/lang/System.html#arraycopy(java.lang.Object, int, java.lang.Object, int, int)">System.arraycopy()</a> method, so most things that apply there are inherited.
]]></description>

</root>
