<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<root>
<name>PFont</name>

<category>Typography</category>

<subcategory>PFont</subcategory>

<type></type>

<example>
<image>PFont.png</image>
<code><![CDATA[
PFont font;
// The font must be located in the sketch's 
// "data" directory to load successfully
font = loadFont("LetterGothicStd-32.vlw");
textFont(font, 32);
text("word", 10, 50);
]]></code>
</example>

<js_mode>
	<description><![CDATA[
Font support for the canvas element varies across browsers. Firefox currently has the best support, but still uses a pre-defined set of fonts. Good alternatives to the browser's canvas-font functions are available: such as the <a href="http://bocoup.com/processing-js/docs/index.php?page=Cross-Browser%20Canvas%20Fonts">Glyph method</a>. See also: <a href="http://jim.studt.net/canvastext/">Canvas Text</a>, <a href="http://canvas.burnttoys.net/bauhaus.html">BurntToys Bauhaus</a>.
<br /><br />
<p><b>Please use the following demos to learn how fonts can be rendered in Firefox with Processing.js: <a href="http://processingjs.org/learning/basic/letters">Letters</a>, <a href="http://processingjs.org/learning/basic/words">Words</a>, <a href="http://processingjs.org/source/text-width/text-width.html">width()</a></b></p>
]]></description>
</js_mode>

<description><![CDATA[
PFont is the font class for Processing. To create a font to use with Processing, select "Create Font..." from the Tools menu. This will create a font in the format Processing requires and also adds it to the current sketch's data directory. Processing displays fonts using the .vlw font format, which uses images for each letter, rather than defining them through vector data. The <b>loadFont()</b> function constructs a new font and <b>textFont()</b> makes a font active. The <b>list()</b> method creates a list of the fonts installed on the computer, which is useful information to use with the <b>createFont()</b> function for dynamically converting fonts into a format to use with Processing. 
]]></description>

</root>
