<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<root>
<name>text()</name>

<category>Typography</category>

<subcategory>Loading &amp; Displaying</subcategory>

<type></type>

<example>
<image>text_0.png</image>
<code><![CDATA[
textSize(32);
text("word", 10, 30); 
fill(0, 102, 153);
text("word", 10, 60);
fill(0, 102, 153, 51);
text("word", 10, 90); 
]]></code>
</example>

<example>
<image>text_1.png</image>
<code><![CDATA[
size(100, 100, P3D);
textSize(32);
fill(0, 102, 153, 204);
text("word", 12, 45, -30);  // Specify a z-axis value
text("word", 12, 60);  // Default depth, no z-value specified
]]></code>
</example>

<example>
<image>text_2.png</image>
<code><![CDATA[
String s = "The quick brown fox jumped over the lazy dog.";
fill(50);
text(s, 10, 10, 70, 80);  // Text wraps within text box
]]></code>
</example>

<!-- js_mode>
	<description><![CDATA[
Please see this page for details on font handling in JavaScript mode:
http://wiki.processing.org/w/Font_handling_in_JavaScript_mode
]]></description>
</js_mode -->

<description><![CDATA[
Draws text to the screen. Displays the information specified in the first parameter on the screen in the position specified by the additional parameters. A default font will be used unless a font is set with the <b>textFont()</b> function and a default size will be used unless a font is set with <b>textSize()</b>. Change the color of the text with the <b>fill()</b> function. The text displays in relation to the <b>textAlign()</b> function, which gives the option to draw to the left, right, and center of the coordinates.<br/>
<br/>
The <b>x2</b> and <b>y2</b> parameters define a rectangular area to display within and may only be used with string data. When these parameters are specified, they are interpreted based on the current <b>rectMode()</b> setting. Text that does not fit completely within the rectangle specified will not be drawn to the screen.<br/>
<br/>
Note that Processing now lets you call <b>text()</b> without first specifying a PFont with <b>textFont()</b>. In that case, a generic sans-serif font will be used instead. (See the third example above.)
]]></description>

</root>
